Carolina Power and Light Photograph Collection PHC.68
State Archives of North Carolina
- Raleigh Cotton Mills, Raleigh, NC c. 1909. Interior and exterior view of Raleigh Cotton Mill in Raleigh, NC. 15 May 1909 Interior view shows picker room before installation of individual drive., PhC.68.1.343.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Richmond Cotton Mill, Laurel Hill, NC c. 1910. Exterior view of Richmond Cotton Mill in Laurel Hill, NC c. 1910., PhC.68.1.344; Carolina Power and Light
- Roberdel Manufacturing Company, Mill No. 1, Rockingham, NC c. 1910. Exterior view of the Roberdel Manufacturing Company, Mill Number One in Rockingham, NC c. 1910., PhC.68.1.345.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Roberdel Manufacturing Company, Mill No. 2, Rockingham, NC c. 1910. Two interior views of the Roberdel Mill No. Two in Rockingham, NC. Shows overall view of room and close view of an individual loom. c. 1910., PhC.68.1.346.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Roberdel Cotton Mills, Rockingham, NC c. 1913. Three separate photographs show overall exterior views of the Roberdel Cotton Mill with workers leaving the factory, January, 1913; the Roberdel Manufacturing Company, Mill # 2, at Rockingham, Richmond County, North Carolina; and Mill # 2, with two hundred thirty (230) horse power in motors installed in two miles by the Yadkin River Power Company, January, 1913., PhC.68.1.347.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Substation Serving Roberdel Mill, Rockingham, NC c. 1914. Exterior view of the Yadkin River Power Company Substation serving the Roberdel Mill # 2 in Rockingham, NC c. 1914, PhC.68.1.348; Carolina Power and Light
- Sanford Cotton Mills, Sanford, NC c. 1909. Exterior view of Sanford Cotton Mills in Sanford, NC 25 May 1909., PhC.68.1.349.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Scotland Cotton Mill, Laurinburg, NC c. 1910. Exterior view of Scotland Cotton Mill in Laurinburg, NC c. 1910, PhC.68.1.350; Carolina Power and Light
- Springfield Cotton Mill, Laurel Hill, NC c. 1910. Photograph shows a view of the Springfield Cotton Mill with firewood stacked beside it. Laurel Hill, NC c. 1910, PhC.68.1.351; Carolina Power and Light
- Steele's Cotton Mill, Rockingham, NC c. 1910. Two exterior views of Steele's Cotton Mills in Rockingham, NC c. 1910, PhC.68.1.352.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Tolar Hart and Holt Cotton Mill, Fayetteville, NC c. 1909. Exterior view of the Tolar Hart and Holt Cotton Mill in Fayetteville, NC 5 June 1909, PhC.68.1.353; Carolina Power and Light
- Victory Cotton Mills, Fayetteville, NC c. 1909. Two exterior views of Victory Cotton Mills in Fayetteville, NC 5 June 1909., PhC.68.1.354.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro Cotton Mills, Wadesboro, NC c. 1910. Two exterior views of the Wadesboro Cotton Mills Company in Wadesboro, NC c. 1910, PhC.68.1.355.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- White Oak Cotton Mills, Interior and Basement, Greensboro, NC c. 1920., PhC.68.1.356.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- J. G. Barbour and Sons Cotton Gin, Clayton, NC c. 1910. Workers are seen loading and weighing cotton bales on the loading dock at J. G. Barbour and Sons Cotton Gin, at Clayton, Johnston County, North Carolina, circa 1910. Photograph is captioned, "A typical cotton gin. The J. G. Barbour and Sons gin, Clayton, NC Served by Carolina Power and Light Co. 50 HP of motors connected.", PhC.68.1.357.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- W. A. Myatt, Jr. and Co. Ginners and Seed Dealers, Raleigh, NC c. 1920. Exterior view of wagons loaded with cotton bales processioning through the W. A. Myatt, Jr. and Company Ginners and Seed Dealers on South Blount Street in Raleigh, North Carolina. c. 1920, PhC.68.1.358; Carolina Power and Light
- Hamer Oil Mills, Hamer, SC c. 1915, PhC.68.1.359; Carolina Power and Light
- Bennettsville Cotton Oil Company, Bennettsville, SC c. 1920. Exterior view of the Bennettsville Cotton Oil Company. Railroad cars are seen at side of building with a man standing in the door of one of the cars. Bennettsville, South Carolina c. 1920., PhC.68.1.360; Carolina Power and Light
- Darlington Cotton Oil Company, Darlington, SC c. 1920. Cotton bales are seen outside the Darlington Cotton Oil Company in Darlington, South Carolina. c. 1920, PhC.68.1.361; Carolina Power and Light
- Dillon Oil Mill, Dillon, SC c. 1915. Exterior view of a branch of The Southern Cotton Oil Company, Dillon Oil Mill in Dillon, SC. The Atlantic Coast Line Railroad is shown being loaded at the facility. c. 1915, PhC.68.1.362; Carolina Power and Light
- Hamer Oil Mills, Hamer, SC c. 1915. Photograph shows an overall exterior view of the Hamer Oil Mills, in Hamer, SC c. 1915., PhC.68.1.363; Carolina Power and Light
- Maxton Cotton Oil Company, Maxton, NC c. 1915. Exterior view of the Maxton Cotton Oil Company, at Maxton, NC. The factory is in the process of being constructed. A rail car is seen alongside the partially constructed building. Maxton, NC c. 1915, PhC.68.1.364; Carolina Power and Light
- Pee Dee Oil Mill, Darlington, SC c. 1915. Exterior view of the Pee Dee Oil Mill, cotton bales are seen on loading dock in front of railroad. Darlington, SC c. 1915, PhC.68.1.365; Carolina Power and Light
- American Agricultural Chemical Company, Henderson, NC 24 October 1923. Exterior view of American Agricultural Chemical Company. A water tower can be seen in foreground, plant is in distance. Henderson, North Carolina, 24 October 1923, PhC.68.1.366; Carolina Power and Light
- Borden Brick and Tile Company, Goldsboro, NC c. 1920. Two photographs show exterior views of the Borden Brick and Tile Company, with automobiles parked outside. Goldsboro, NC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.367.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Unidentified Brick Plant in Goldsboro, NC c. 1920. Exterior photograph of an unidentified brick plant in Goldsboro, NC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.368; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Fibre Company, Hartsville, SC c. 1920. Exterior view of the Carolina Fibre Company in Hartsville, SC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.369; Carolina Power and Light
- Municipal Waterworks, Goldsboro, NC 24 October 1923. Exterior view of the Municipal Waterworks in Goldsboro, NC. A cotton field can be seen in the foreground. 24 October 1923, PhC.68.1.370; Carolina Power and Light
- Darlington Ice Plant, Darlington, SC c. 1920. Exterior view of the Darlington Ice Plant in Darlington, SC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.371; Carolina Power and Light
- Elk Mountain Power Plant, Asheville, NC c. 1915. Exterior view of the Elk Mountain Steam Generating Plant. Smoke is seen billowing from stack. Located on French Broad River in Asheville, NC c. 1915, PhC.68.1.372; Carolina Power and Light
- Hammond Flour Mills, Inc., Laurinburg, NC c. 1920. Exterior view of the Hammond Flour Mills Incorporated. Reverse of photo is captioned, "A typical flour mill and grain elevator served by the Yadkin river Power Company, at Laurinburg, Scotland County, North Carolina 200 HP of motors connected". c. 1920, PhC.68.1.373.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- R. G. Lassiter Cement Plant, Oxford, NC c.1915. View of workers with equipment and trucks at the Robert G. Lassiter Cement Plant in Oxford, NC c. 1915, PhC.68.1.374; Carolina Power and Light
- Maxton Manufacturing Company, Maxton, NC c.1915. Exterior view of the Maxton Manufacturing Company in Maxton, NC c. 1915, PhC.68.1.375; Carolina Power and Light
- Construction Work on New Railroad, Wadesboro, NC c. 1910. View of a steam shovel at work on the construction of a new railroad through Wadesboro, NC c. 1910, PhC.68.1.376; Carolina Power and Light
- Seaboard Airline Railway Shops and Power Plant, Hamlet, NC c. 1921. Two separate photographs show: the Seaboard Air Line Railway Power Plant and adjacent roundhouse with locomotive wheels in the foreground; and three unidentified Carolina Power and Light Company employees with their utility vehicles beside a transformer. Truck seen in the photo is a Nash Quad c. 1918 Hamlet, NC 6 January 1921., PhC.68.1.377.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- J. P. Taylor Company Leaf Tobacco, Goldsboro, NC c. 1920. Exterior view of the J. P. Taylor Company Leaf Tobacco Stemmery and Dryer in Goldsboro, NC. Reverse of photograph is captioned, "A typical tobacco stemmery and dryer. Served by Carolina Power and Light at Goldsboro, NC. 75 hp of motors connected" c. 1920., PhC.68.1.378; Carolina Power and Light
- Virginia Carolina Chemical Company, Wadesboro, NC c. 1913. Exterior views of the Virginia Carolina Chemical Company, from various angles, at Wadesboro, Anson County, North Carolina. Photos taken January, 1913., PhC.68.1.379.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Wadesboro Chair Manufacturing Company, Wadesboro, NC c. 1920. Exterior view of the Wadesboro Chair Manufacturing Company, during construction of a water tower, at Wadesboro, Anson County, North Carolina. c. 1920, PhC.68.1.380; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Sales Office Interior, Dunn, NC c. 1923. Interior view of the Carolina Power and Light office in Dunn, NC. Various products are seen displayed in cabinets along the wall and on the floor. Dunn, NC c. 1923, PhC.68.1.381; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Office/Showroom, Raleigh, NC c. 1923. Two interior views of the Carolina Power and Light office/showroom in Raleigh, NC c. 1923. Various products are seen on display including heaters, ovens, toasters, Hoover vacuum cleaners, lightbulbs, etc. A Christmas tree is seen in one of the pictures., PhC.68.1.382; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Showroom Display Case, Hamlet, NC c. 1925. Front view of a display case in Hamlet, NC displaying a variety of electrical appliances including, toasters, waffle irons, coffee makers, lamps, insulators, fuses, and Mazda Edison light bulbs. Hamlet, NC c. 1925, PhC.68.1.383; Carolina Power and Light
- Christmas Appliance Display c. 1925. A Christmas window display is seen with various small electric appliances. A waffle iron, toaster, clothes iron, light socket, lamps, and a curling iron are pictured on display. c. 1925, PhC.68.1.384; Carolina Power and Light
- Model Kitchen on Electric Streetcar, Raleigh, NC c. 1930. A street car is seen on Martin Street in Raleigh with the Wachovia building in background. A model kitchen with two men, a woman and an African American woman riding are seen. Raleigh, NC c. 1930, PhC.68.1.385; Carolina Power and Light
- Universal Appliances Display, Roxboro, NC c. 1930s. A marketing display for Universal Appliance is seen set up on a table inside of a Carolina Power and Light office. Various appliances including, coffee makers, electric alarm clocks, an electric iron, an electric toaster and lamps are seen. Roxboro, NC c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.386.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Electric Appliance Exhibit c. 1930. A Carolina Power and Light exhibit is seen set up with decorations highlighting a range of electric kitchen appliances such as ovens, ice boxes and water heaters. c. 1930, PhC.68.1.387; Carolina Power and Light
- Appliance Display in Raleigh Office, Raleigh, NC c.1940. A woman is seen in the Raleigh Carolina Power and Light Office demonstrating a Frigidaire refrigerator. A Bendix Home Laundry and a Gibson Refrigerator are seen to the left. c. 1940, PhC.68.1.388; Carolina Power and Light
- Electric Appliances in Store Window Displays c. 1940. Store window displays are seen of various kitchen and home electric appliances. Refrigerators, vacuum cleaners, General Electric ovens, and others are seen in two separate store windows promoting a sales contest. One photograph shows a Universal Electric oven in a store window Christmas display. Cotton balls are seen tied to string to imitate snow. c. 1940, PhC.68.1.389.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Store Displays of Kitchen Appliances, Asheville, NC. c. 1940. Various displays of kitchen appliances in various stores and store windows in Asheville, NC. Model kitchens and store displays are seen with ovens, refrigerators, washing machines, etc. A salesman is seen talking to three women about a refrigerator. Two photographs from Reusing's in Asheville, other stores seen are Cut Rate Furniture Co. and Railroad Salvage. c. 1940, PhC.68.1.390.1-6; Carolina Power and Light
- Store Window Displays c. 1940. Pictured are two store window displays at the same location at different times. One depicts a Christmas display with small electric appliances including mixers, clocks, coffee makers, waffle irons and toasters. Second photograph depicts a window display solely for Silex brand coffee makers. c. 1940, PhC.68.1.391.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing Displays, Kitchen Appliances. Various marketing displays for kitchen appliances including ovens, refrigerators and washing machines. Salesmen are seen selling product in showrooms, model kitchens are seen, and an exhibit on the evolution of residential electricity use. c. 1940s-1960s, PhC.68.1.392.1-6; Carolina Power and Light
- Appliances Outdoors In Front of Residences c. 1930. Appliances are seen in front of a residence in the front yard. Included are, a vacuum, refrigerator, washing machine, radio, waffle maker, coffee pot, toaster, space heater, oven clock and iron. Also included is a photograph of 10 ovens on a sidewalk in front of what appears to be an apartment building. c. 1930, PhC.68.1.393-1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Electric Appliance Displays c. 1950. Three photographs depicting various electric appliance displays. Lightbulbs, an electric mixer, an electric fan, waffle iron, iron, coffee pot, toaster, heater and photographic equipment are all seen. c. 1940s-1950's, PhC.68.1.394.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Various Electric Appliance Marketing Photographs c. 1950., PhC.68.1.395.1-7; Carolina Power and Light
  - Westinghouse televisions are seen displayed with other promotional materials on a stage. Three men and a woman are seen. One man is pointing to a promotional banner., PhC.68.1.395.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two men are seen with a promotional display for Westinghouse stackable washing machine and dryer., PhC.68.1.395.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two women are seen posing with an electric washing machine and a dryer. Back of photograph is captioned, "Holmes Electric Inc. Fayetteville- From ______ ____, Dunn., PhC.68.1.395.3; Carolina Power and Light
  - Display window is seen for Burney Hardware Co. Various Frigidaire appliances are seen displayed in window., PhC.68.1.395.4; Carolina Power and Light
  - Display window is seen for Burney Hardware Co. Various Frigidaire appliances are seen displayed in window., PhC.68.1.395.5; Carolina Power and Light
  - Two men are seen shaking hands as one accepts a Wizard Cleaner as first prize in a drawing. Other employees are standing behind them., PhC.68.1.395.6; Carolina Power and Light
  - Photograph is inscribed on reverse, "Mrs. Shirley Hinson, visitor and likely prospect at Purdie's Inc. gala opening is getting the lowdown on the new 1954 GE refrigerator from Mr. J.W. Purdie, owner of Purdie's Inc.", PhC.68.1.395.7; Carolina Power and Light
- Traveling Mobile Display Trailer, Sound Appliance Co. Inc. Morehead City, NC. c. 1950. Pictured is a trailer outfitted to be a mobile display unit for Sound Appliance Co., Inc. A small girl is standing in doorway of trailer as two men shake hands at front of trailer. c. 1950, PhC.68.1.396; Carolina Power and Light
- Billboard on Fayetteville Street, Raleigh, NC c. 1920. A billboard promoting electric power is seen over the building on the south eastern corner of Hargett and Fayetteville Streets in Raleigh, NC. Shop on the corner is Uzzle's Cigar Store. Raleigh, NC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.397; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Billboard and Store Display c. 1930. A Carolina Power and Light billboard is seen advertising electrical household products as Christmas gifts. Also seen is a store display with various products including an electric iron, waffle maker lamps, curling iron, electric sewing motor, and an electric coffee pot. c. 1930, PhC.68.1.398.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Billboard For Carolina Power and Light c. 1925. Pictured is a large billboard with an advertisement that reads, "Duplex-a-lite The light to live with, Carolina Power and Light Co." c. 1925, PhC.68.1.399; Carolina Power and Light
- Billboard For Electric Washing Machine-Carolina Power and Light c. 1925. A billboard is seen for an electric washing machine. "Ask for a Home Demonstration, Automatic Electric Washer, 'Cleans clothes clean' $5.00 Down, $5.00 a month-Carolina Power and Light". c. 1925, PhC.68.1.400.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Billboard For Contest to Win Electrified Home-Carolina Power and Light c. 1930. Pictured is a billboard for Carolina Power and Light advertising a contest to win a $15,000 electrified home. The billboard reads, "This $15,000 Electrical Home-free-Watch for the announcement!-Carolina Power and Light". c. 1930, PhC.68.1.401; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Window Unit Air Conditioner c. 1945. Pictured is an office scene with a man and a woman at a desk by a window with a window unit air conditioner. There is an arrow pointing towards the air conditioner. c. 1945, PhC.68.1.402; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Cooking Class c. 1950. Pictured are women seated in a classroom taking notes. They are also seen in a kitchen, cooking. c. 1950, PhC.68.1.403.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- National Cotton Week Display-Carolina Power and Light c. 1945. Carolina Power and Light National Cotton Week display. Small articles of clothing and samples of cotton and cotton related products are seen displayed to promote North Carolina's cotton industry. c. 1945, PhC.68.1.404; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Illustration of 1924 Dishwasher. An illustration of a 1924 electric dishwasher is seen loaded with dishes. c. 1920s, PhC.68.1.405; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Carolina Power and Light/Yadkin Power Company Marketing Display. Pictured are scenes from the Carolina Power and Light and Yadkin River Power Company's booth/exhibit at the International Textile Exhibition in Boston Mass. Graphics, maps, advertisements and photographs are seen in the exhibit. April 1926., PhC.68.1.406.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Carolina Power and Light/Yadkin Power Company Marketing Display. Pictured is a promotional display for Knitting Arts in Philadelphia, PA. Maps, graphics and photographs are seen displayed promoting North Carolina's cotton and electric industry. March 1926, PhC.68.1.407; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Electric Fan Display c. 1930s. Pictured is a display for Emerson Electric fans. Five fans are seen on display with graphics that read, "When the city sizzles, keep cool" Possibly set up in the Raleigh, NC Carolina Power and Light office. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.408; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Advertisement for Electric Exhaust Fan c. 1940s. Pictured is a woman standing at a stove, stirring a pot of food. A thin plume of smoke is seen rising from the pot as it floats up to the exhaust vent. Used in an advertisement for an exhaust fan. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.409; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Garbage Disposal c. 1936. A man is seen standing at a model sink with exposed pipes to demonstrate the workings of a garbage disposal. He is seen with a drain catcher in one hand and pointing to the sink with the other. c. 1936, PhC.68.1.410; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Heater Advertising Photograph-Two Girls c. 1920. Two girls approximately 4-5 years old are seen standing naked, warming themselves with a household space heater. They are seen looking over their shoulder towards camera with their hands out over the heater. c. 1920, PhC.68.1.411; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Woman Ironing Using Non-Electric Iron. A woman is seen using an old non-electric iron to iron fabrics on an ironing board. Used for marketing purposes for Carolina Power and Light. c. 1920s, PhC.68.1.412; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Woman Seen Using an Electric Iron c. 1920s. A woman is seen using an electric iron on what looks like a dress. Used for marketing purposes for Carolina Power and Light. c. 1924, PhC.68.1.413; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing- Woman Using Electric Ironing Press c. 1950s. A woman is seen using an electric ironing press c. 1950s. Used for marketing purposes for Carolina Power and Light., PhC.68.1.414.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Women Seen in Kitchen. Two photographs of different women in two different kitchens. One shows a woman standing next to an electric oven from the 1920's the other shows a woman in a kitchen possibly putting away or cleaning dishes. Used for marketing purposes for Carolina Power and Light, PhC.68.1.415.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Kitchen Displays and Appliances. A kitchen appliance display is seen with electric ovens, electric water heaters and an electric refrigerator. Also seen are several scenes of staged kitchens. One is an older kitchen without electric appliances and one is a newer looking kitchen with new, electric appliances. c. 1950's, PhC.68.1.416.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Electric Home Traveling Demonstration. Series of images of a vehicle and trailer used to demonstrate and educate the public on electric service. A white 1930 REO coupe is seen connected to a trailer outfitted with a model kitchen with electric appliances. Interior of trailer is seen in one picture with two salesmen/representatives inside. Trailer is seen from front and left sides. The trailer is also pictured in front of the NC State Bell Tower with a group of ~30 female school children. The car and trailer were taken to rural areas to familiarize with electric service for the first, PhC.68.1.417.1-9; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Kitchens. Five 8x10 black and white prints and one color 8x10 print of kitchens dating from the late 1950s to the 1970s. Women, men, and children are seen in kitchens preparing food, posing, and eating., PhC.68.1.418.1-6; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Lighting, Early Edison Bulb. Black and white photograph of an early Edison light bulb with a red transparency of the outline of the image. The transparency is taped on top of the photograph. c. 1950, PhC.68.1.419; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Mazda Edison Light Bulbs on Display in Asheville, NC Office c. 1922. Pictured is a Mazda Edison Light Bulb display in the Asheville, NC Carolina Power and Light office c. 1922. Different types of bulbs are seen displayed and boxes of product are seen stacked on shelfs. Two cut outs of women holding bulbs are also seen., PhC.68.1.420; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Mazda Edison Light Bulb Display. Pictured is a table top display of various types of Mazda Edison Light Bulbs. Boxes are seen displayed with promotional material and the light bulbs. c. 1920, PhC.68.1.421; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing Edison Light Bulb Display c. 1930s-40s. Two Mazda Edison light bulbs are seen c. 1930s-40s. Light bulbs are seen arranged and displayed in and out of boxes with promotional material., PhC.68.1.422.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Streetlight, Globe Lamp. Pictured is a close view of a streetlight bracket, fixture and globe. c. 1920s, PhC.68.1.423.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Electric Lamp Display, Carolina Power and Light Office c. 1925. Pictured is an electric lamp display in a Carolina Power and Light office. Various style floor and table lamps are seen turned on and on display. c. 1925, PhC.68.1.424; Carolina Power and Light
- Marketing-Domestic Interior Lit With Electric Lights. A domestic interior is seen lit with electric lights. Wall sconces, overhead lights, and a table lamp are seen above and around a fireplace with a desk and table near it. c. 1925, PhC.68.1.425; Carolina Power and Light